<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on m-fra.me</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on m-fra.me</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 09:59:46 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts About Endpoint Management Software</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/endpointmanagementsoftware/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 09:59:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/endpointmanagementsoftware/</guid>
      <description>Over the past year I have worked a bit on expanding my knowledge of configuration management / endpoint management software (such as Ansible, and Intune).
Ansible Ansible in my opinion is wonderful, historically i&amp;rsquo;ve used shell scripts to manage my Linux nodes but Ansible allows me to actually see @ a glance if my configuration applied or not. With shell scripts I&amp;rsquo;d run my script against the node and i&amp;rsquo;d have to verify that it applied correctly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Build Things</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/how_i_build_things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 13:40:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/how_i_build_things/</guid>
      <description>Before AI, I typically started out with an idea of what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to accomplish based on some need that I have.
I write out a list of steps that I need to accomplish said task.
After my list is written out I would fill in the details beneath each step (like how I would accomplish subtasks to accomplish the overaching step).
If I am writing a script I would then decide of each step should be a function or if it&amp;rsquo;s okay to just write the code in my main execution area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Need to Buy New Things</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/the-need-to-buy-new-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 21:12:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/the-need-to-buy-new-things/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you but I have a strong compulsion to buy new and novel things.
I think this was programmed into me by watching an absolute ton of television when I was younger, seeing all the Pokemon, Street Sharks, Beetleborgs, Power Ranger commercials as well as all the video game magazines that I used to read.
Now I know that I really don&amp;rsquo;t need to buy whatever the latest thing is and I do my best to resist the call.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tasty tomato boullion rice</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/tasty_tomato_boullion_rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 23:32:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/tasty_tomato_boullion_rice/</guid>
      <description>My favorite side dish is rice. One way to make rice better though is to add a bit of tomato boullion into it (instead of salt).
 First you take 1 cup of rice Add it into the rice cooker with 1.5 cups of water Add about a teaspoon of tomato boullion. I use the tomato boullion pictured above Let the rice cooker work it&amp;rsquo;s magic (wait till it finishes cooking the rice).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On being frugal</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/on_being_frugal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 08:34:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/on_being_frugal/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s good to be frugal, try to participate in the circular economy on Facebook Marketplace.
You really only need a computer, a tv and a phone, all other electronics are bloat.
A 6th gen intel i5 with 16 gb of ram can run pretty much everything that is needed for programming at the level that you operate at. If you are doing anything that requires more compute or gpu resources it is cheaper (or free) to use cloud services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podman Tui</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/podman-tui/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 23:32:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/podman-tui/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m really into doing things as simply as possible. Because of this, I spend countless hours searching across the internet to find new and better ways to accomplish my goals.
In my searches I came across a program called &amp;ldquo;podman-tui&amp;rdquo;.
Podman-tui simplifies container administration w/ podman. Best part is it is available in the repositories for RHEL (so you can use it @ your job).
Below is a gif taken from the github page for podman-tui, really cool stuff, much better than memorizing a bunch of commands when you&amp;rsquo;re first getting into containers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That&#39;s alot of words</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/thats_alot_of_words/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 00:17:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/thats_alot_of_words/</guid>
      <description>Too Bad i&amp;rsquo;m not readin em
On my first run through college (2007 &amp;ndash; 2011). I had an English professor named Pagaard (pronounced Pay Guard as he would always say).
Pagaard&amp;rsquo;s philosophy was that you should use as few words as possible while fully explaining what you are trying to communicate. Pagaard&amp;rsquo;s main thought on this subject was that language is used for communication, if you use too many words you can muddy the waters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on automating my life</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/thoughts_on_automating_my_life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 23:37:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/thoughts_on_automating_my_life/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PXE server configuration - Homelab - Ethernet NIC on back of AIO computer</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/pxeserverconfig/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 20:12:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/pxeserverconfig/</guid>
      <description>Background: Recently I began expanding my homelab. Historically @ home I used usb drives to flash linux onto new computers that I purchased but I was getting tired of losing said usb drives.
Because of this I began thinking about how i&amp;rsquo;ve imaged devices in the past. I remembered that once, at one of the companies I worked at I configured a PXE server such that I could image about 30 laptops for a programming interview/test that the company was doing so that they could hire more people.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
